<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>MovingToMexico on The Expat Tech</title>
    <link>https://zdevilinside.github.io/TheExpatTech/categories/movingtomexico/</link>
    <description>Recent content in MovingToMexico on The Expat Tech</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://zdevilinside.github.io/TheExpatTech/categories/movingtomexico/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How and why I moved to Mexico?</title>
      <link>https://zdevilinside.github.io/TheExpatTech/posts/living-in-mexico/the-big-move/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://zdevilinside.github.io/TheExpatTech/posts/living-in-mexico/the-big-move/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I got in my van and drove there! ;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Okay, I will be serious.  I really didn&amp;rsquo;t have a choice but to move.  In my case, I had just come home from a failed attempt to start school in Germany.  We were in a bad situation - we had sold our house already, needed to move to somewhere for 6 months and live on a student&amp;rsquo;s budget.  We needed to have good Internet, be near a major international airport, and inexpensive.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Adventures in Moving - Day 3</title>
      <link>https://zdevilinside.github.io/TheExpatTech/posts/living-in-mexico/adventures-in-moving-day-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://zdevilinside.github.io/TheExpatTech/posts/living-in-mexico/adventures-in-moving-day-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The next morning, I get up, get on my laptop and contact a friend from boarding school that lives in Mexico City.  Pedro gives me some tips for the rest of my trip into Mexico - always tip people 10 pesos or so if they fill your gas tank (Mexico is a &amp;ldquo;full service&amp;rdquo; country where you cannot fill your own gas tank!), and gives us the name of the place to go to exchange our US dollars for pesos.  Dipshit Farmers had gone to Mexico before but they took US dollars and we thought it was that way still.  NOPE!  Mexico implemented new rules that was intended to stop money-laundering.  Anyhow, Pedro tells us to go to a &amp;ldquo;casa de cambio&amp;rdquo; to get that done.  We find one on the map and program it into my wife&amp;rsquo;s GPS.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Adventures in Moving - Day 2</title>
      <link>https://zdevilinside.github.io/TheExpatTech/posts/living-in-mexico/adventures-in-moving-day-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://zdevilinside.github.io/TheExpatTech/posts/living-in-mexico/adventures-in-moving-day-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We wake up the next morning and it is late - 11 AM or so.  We wanted to sleep and be on the road by 9am but that just didn&amp;rsquo;t happen.  I sneak the cats back into the van and we start on the move once more.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As we are driving away, we noticed that the air conditioneer wasn&amp;rsquo;t blowing cold.  I had just put freon in yesterday before we left Albuquerque!!!!  I decide to go get more freon and put it in in the parking lot by the Motel 6.  When I go to put it in, I noticed my error.  I forgot to put the cap on the line yesterday so all the freon came out!!!  I can be an idiot at times!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Adventures in Moving - Day 1</title>
      <link>https://zdevilinside.github.io/TheExpatTech/posts/living-in-mexico/adventures-in-moving-day-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://zdevilinside.github.io/TheExpatTech/posts/living-in-mexico/adventures-in-moving-day-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Moving to Mexico was a rushed endeavor for us.  We were moving down to Mexico in a used minivan that we bought just for the move.  You cannot rent a U-Haul to move across international borders.  The van we bought has cheap and the plan was to get to Mexico and then just get rid of it.  That turns out not to be something you can do.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To say we were not properly prepared for this move is an understatement of the century.  We were basing things on what we knew about living in the United States, and from our couple of trips to Puerto Penasco, Mexico AKA Rocky Point, or, as my girlfriend at the time kept calling Pina Colada because she was drunk.  Needless to say, things changed!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
