<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Digital Nomad on The Expat Tech</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/digital-nomading/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Digital Nomad on The Expat Tech</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 19:35:49 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/digital-nomading/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What is a Digital Nomad VPN?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/digital-nomading/what-is-a-digital-nomad-vpn/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 19:35:49 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/digital-nomading/what-is-a-digital-nomad-vpn/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;digital-nomad-vpn-guide&#34;&gt;Digital Nomad VPN Guide&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s start this off with a few explanations so you can better understand some basic concepts.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;First, think of the Internet as a giant map. There are addresses where you can access specific things, and only those addresses. To reach them, you type in something like &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.IDontWantToBeHere.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener noreffer &#34;&gt;www.IDontWantToBeHere.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; (I don’t think that site actually exists) and hit enter in your web browser. Most people don’t know how that actually works. Your Internet provider takes that website’s URL and looks it up in a “phone book” until it finds a “phone number” used to dial that location. When you enter that address, the phone book shows the address &lt;em&gt;127.0.0.1&lt;/em&gt; and dials that number. It’s that simple.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Digital Nomad VPN Setup</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/digital-nomading/digital-nomad-vpn-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/digital-nomading/digital-nomad-vpn-setup/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;top-secret---unauthorized-personnel-will-be-shot-if-they-continue-to-read-this-post&#34;&gt;Top Secret - Unauthorized personnel will be shot if they continue to read this post&amp;hellip;..&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Okay, you have made the decision.  You want to take a chance with your job and work from somewhere that you are not authorized.  You now need to set things up so that you can make it the least likely to get caught.  You agree not to hold me responsible for any outcome you have if you are caught doing what I am about to show you how to do.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Becoming a Digital Nomad</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/digital-nomading/becoming-a-digital-nomad/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/digital-nomading/becoming-a-digital-nomad/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You are feeling wunderlust.  Your job is online so you feel that you can start working from anywhere.  You decide to give it a go.  You look online at the rules needed to travel the world while working online.  That is how you get your start.  This site will explain &lt;em&gt;my&lt;/em&gt; path down this rabbit hole.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In my case, it came about as a necessity.  I was on my way to graduate school in Germany when that was cut short due to illness.  I looked around and did research online for the best places to go and live for 6 months before I gave another shot at going to Germany.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to my world</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/digital-nomading/welcome-to-my-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/digital-nomading/welcome-to-my-world/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;well-what-is-this-site&#34;&gt;Well, what is this site?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I want to create a place where I can share the things I enjoy, the things I know well, and the things I’ve spent a lifetime immersed in. I know a lot about computers. I’m an American who lives part-time in Mexico, part-time in the U.S., and part-time all over the world. I’ve worked professionally as an IT technician for over three decades. I also know quite a bit about how to entertain yourself if you&amp;rsquo;re an indoor person who likes movies and TV shows.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How I became a digital nomad?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/digital-nomading/how-i-became-a-digital-nomad/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/digital-nomading/how-i-became-a-digital-nomad/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was on my way to graduate school in Germany back in 2015.  I got as far as Amsterdam when I ended up being hospitalized for 15 days.  7 days in was when graduate school started.  The Germans wouldn&amp;rsquo;t let me have a late start so I had to return to the US.  We had already sold our house by then so I needed to move somewhere fast.  My requirements were that the place was inexpensive, had great internet service, was near a major international airport, and that &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;snow&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo; was a foreign language and the only ice you got was in your drink.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
