<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>All All Posts - The Expat Tech</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/TheExpatTech/posts/</link>
        <description>All All Posts | The Expat Tech</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 00:00:00 &#43;0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/TheExpatTech/posts/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>Tech Tips</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/TheExpatTech/posts/tech-tips/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>ZDevilInside</author>
    <guid>http://localhost:1313/TheExpatTech/posts/tech-tips/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>I have been working in comptuers for a number of years and have come to the point where I don&rsquo;t really see nothing anymore I haven&rsquo;t seen previously in one form or another.  I am going to provide tips about things I have learned and how-to&rsquo;s to do various things in this area.  I hope the &ldquo;grey beards&rdquo; I know will help me with providing information to be shared with others here.</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Digital Nomad</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/TheExpatTech/posts/digital-nomading/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 19:35:49 -0600</pubDate>
    <author>ZDevilInside</author>
    <guid>http://localhost:1313/TheExpatTech/posts/digital-nomading/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>I may not know much about how to get an online job, I can give you information on my experiences.  I know how to do things that are technical in nature to help you with your nomad experience.  I won&rsquo;t help you get a job, get around rules/regulations of places you want to visit, but I <strong>WILL</strong> share with you what I know how to do to make this an easier experience.  Things such as how to setup a Digital Nomad VPN using Wireguard is one such thing.  It is actually quite easy to do.  Unfortunately, I do not have the technical background to answer questions on how to fix it but will share knowledge as I learn it.</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Aviation</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/TheExpatTech/posts/aviation/</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>ZDevilInside</author>
    <guid>http://localhost:1313/TheExpatTech/posts/aviation/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>I have been a fan of aviation for quite some tiome.  I remember reading all I could about various airplanes growing up.  When I was in AFJROTC as a freshman in high school, I started to memorize performance characteristics and dreamed of being a pilot.  I learned as much as I could about flying and went up every time I could.</p>
<p>When I went off to boarding military school, there was an aviation program there where you could learn to fly.  I took lessons there and in the mountains near home when I was on break from school.  I learned so much about aviation that I am wanting to share my knowledge with you.  I will be starting off with lists about my favorite planes, some of their performance specifications that I feel are interesting, and will end with gneeral aviation stories.  I hope you enjoy what I share here.</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Living In Mexico</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/TheExpatTech/posts/living-in-mexico/</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>ZDevilInside</author>
    <guid>http://localhost:1313/TheExpatTech/posts/living-in-mexico/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>This is about my life&rsquo;s experience with moving to Mexico and living there since August 2015.</p>]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
