<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ZDevilInside on The Expat Tech</title>
    <link>https://www.theexpattech.com/authors/zdevilinside/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ZDevilInside on The Expat Tech</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.theexpattech.com/authors/zdevilinside/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Recommended VPN equipment</title>
      <link>https://www.theexpattech.com/digital-nomading/vpn-equipment-i-use/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.theexpattech.com/digital-nomading/vpn-equipment-i-use/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am a true believer in using GL.iNet equipment for setting up Digital Nomad VPNs.  I base this on my history with using the devices.  Originally, I did find out how to set up a VPN server/client by searching the web and letting my eyes roll into the back of my head because there was so much technical information out there.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I found a website that walked you through the setup step by step.  The first thing that they recommened was buying the equipment you would need to actually do the job. ;)  Gee, how many of us have overlooked this vital step?  I certainly had!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Happy Thanksgiving!</title>
      <link>https://www.theexpattech.com/misc/happy-thanksgiving/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.theexpattech.com/misc/happy-thanksgiving/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I want to wish you all a Happy Thanksgiving.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Having said that, I want to share a fun piece of trivia.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Did you know that the &amp;ldquo;star&amp;rdquo; of Thanksgiving dinner, the turkey, is actually Mexican? If you think the turkey is American, you’re mistaken. The turkey is an immigrant. Mexico&amp;rsquo;s Aztecs domesticated the turkey over 2,000 years ago. It was called the huexolotl. They didn’t eat it the way we do today—with gravy and stuffing. The Aztecs ate it with mole.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Qualifying for Legal Residency in Mexico</title>
      <link>https://www.theexpattech.com/living-in-mexico/qualifying-for-legal-residency-in-mexico/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.theexpattech.com/living-in-mexico/qualifying-for-legal-residency-in-mexico/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img&#xA;        class=&#34;lazyload&#34;&#xA;        src=&#34;https://www.theexpattech.com/svg/loading.min.svg&#34;&#xA;        data-src=&#34;https://www.theexpattech.com/living-in-mexico/qualifying-for-legal-residency-in-mexico/card.jpg&#34;&#xA;        data-srcset=&#34;https://www.theexpattech.com/living-in-mexico/qualifying-for-legal-residency-in-mexico/card.jpg, https://www.theexpattech.com/living-in-mexico/qualifying-for-legal-residency-in-mexico/card.jpg 1.5x, https://www.theexpattech.com/living-in-mexico/qualifying-for-legal-residency-in-mexico/card.jpg 2x&#34;&#xA;        data-sizes=&#34;auto&#34;&#xA;        alt=&#34;/living-in-mexico/qualifying-for-legal-residency-in-mexico/card.jpg&#34;&#xA;        title=&#34;image 1&#34; width=&#34;522&#34; height=&#34;314&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So you want to become a resident of Mexico but don&amp;rsquo;t know where to start?  Well, it isn&amp;rsquo;t as easy as just moving to Mexico and you are a resident.  You have to follow specific steps to become one.  If you are thinking of just getting a FMM (AKA Tourist Visa) and live in Mexico on it, those days are rapidly coming to an end.  INM (Mexican Immigration) has now networked their systems so that they can see who is trying to game the system and live in Mexico without follow the legal process.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>It is time to pay annual bonuses</title>
      <link>https://www.theexpattech.com/living-in-mexico/it-is-time-to-pay-annual-bonuses/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.theexpattech.com/living-in-mexico/it-is-time-to-pay-annual-bonuses/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img&#xA;        class=&#34;lazyload&#34;&#xA;        src=&#34;https://www.theexpattech.com/svg/loading.min.svg&#34;&#xA;        data-src=&#34;https://www.theexpattech.com/living-in-mexico/it-is-time-to-pay-annual-bonuses/image1.jpg&#34;&#xA;        data-srcset=&#34;https://www.theexpattech.com/living-in-mexico/it-is-time-to-pay-annual-bonuses/image1.jpg, https://www.theexpattech.com/living-in-mexico/it-is-time-to-pay-annual-bonuses/image1.jpg 1.5x, https://www.theexpattech.com/living-in-mexico/it-is-time-to-pay-annual-bonuses/image1.jpg 2x&#34;&#xA;        data-sizes=&#34;auto&#34;&#xA;        alt=&#34;/living-in-mexico/it-is-time-to-pay-annual-bonuses/image1.jpg&#34;&#xA;        title=&#34;image 1&#34; width=&#34;2034&#34; height=&#34;1296&#34; /&gt;&#xA;It is that time of the year again where workers are given their yearly bonuses.  This is NOT an optional thing either.  Mexico&amp;rsquo;s previous President Andres Manuel Lopez Obrador (AMLO) completely redid the Mexico Ley de Trabajo and this is what it says now:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Article 87.- Workers will have the right to an annual bonus that must be paid before the twentieth of December, equivalent to at least fifteen days of salary. Those who have not completed the year of service, regardless of whether they are working or not on the date of settlement of the bonus, will have the right to be paid the proportional part of it, according to the time they have worked, whatever this may be.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GL.iNet Beryl AX review</title>
      <link>https://www.theexpattech.com/tech-tips/gl.inet-beryl-ax-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.theexpattech.com/tech-tips/gl.inet-beryl-ax-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;-glinet-beryl-ax-gl-mt3000-review&#34;&gt;🌐 GL.iNet Beryl AX (GL-MT3000) Review&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img&#xA;        class=&#34;lazyload&#34;&#xA;        src=&#34;https://www.theexpattech.com/svg/loading.min.svg&#34;&#xA;        data-src=&#34;https://www.theexpattech.com/tech-tips/gl.inet-beryl-ax-review/Tech-Tips/beryl-ax-review/image1.jpg&#34;&#xA;        data-srcset=&#34;https://www.theexpattech.com/tech-tips/gl.inet-beryl-ax-review/Tech-Tips/beryl-ax-review/image1.jpg, https://www.theexpattech.com/tech-tips/gl.inet-beryl-ax-review/Tech-Tips/beryl-ax-review/image1.jpg 1.5x, https://www.theexpattech.com/tech-tips/gl.inet-beryl-ax-review/Tech-Tips/beryl-ax-review/image1.jpg 2x&#34;&#xA;        data-sizes=&#34;auto&#34;&#xA;        alt=&#34;/tech-tips/gl.inet-beryl-ax-review/Tech-Tips/beryl-ax-review/image1.jpg&#34;&#xA;        title=&#34;image 1&#34; width=&#34;1200&#34; height=&#34;1600&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I know this is an older piece of hardware that is about to have its follow on Beryl 7 released but this router is a staple of many a digital nomader&amp;rsquo;s equipment. I have been using one for years without issue and I feel that it is a budget VPN router worth knowing about.  You can easily take it with you, use it in &amp;ldquo;capture portal&amp;rdquo; situations, and it gives you a separate network that all your devices can connect to.  Oh, and it can run a Wireguard client/server as needed along with several other VPN solutions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Resetting a Flipper Zero</title>
      <link>https://www.theexpattech.com/tech-tips/resetting-a-flipper-zero/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 14:35:49 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.theexpattech.com/tech-tips/resetting-a-flipper-zero/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A friend of mine had his Flipper Zero freeze up on them.  They asked me how to get it to reset.  When that didn&amp;rsquo;t work, they decided to do a &amp;ldquo;hard reset&amp;rdquo; of their Flipper but they had difficulty finding the directions on how to do it.  I decided to create this page to help those that are having to look online to find the answer.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Do you have a Flipper Zero that you forgot the pin to?  It is actually quite easy to reset.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Digital Nomad VPN Setup</title>
      <link>https://www.theexpattech.com/digital-nomading/digital-nomad-vpn-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.theexpattech.com/digital-nomading/digital-nomad-vpn-setup/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;-top-secret-notice&#34;&gt;🚨 Top Secret Notice&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unauthorized personnel beware!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;This guide contains sensitive setup instructions.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Proceed at your own risk — and remember, this is for educational purposes only.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Okay, you have made the decision. You want to take a chance with your job and work from somewhere that you are not authorized. You now need to set things up so that you can make it the least likely to get caught. You agree not to hold me responsible for any outcome you have if you are caught doing what I am about to show you how to do.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Build a Mac OS 15 Sequoia VM?</title>
      <link>https://www.theexpattech.com/tech-tips/build-a-mac-os-15-sequoia-vm/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 19:35:49 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.theexpattech.com/tech-tips/build-a-mac-os-15-sequoia-vm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;getting-started&#34;&gt;Getting Started&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to create a MacOS 15 Sequoia VM in VMware&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Over the years, I have noticed that a lot of people seem to have bought into the marketing of Apple and believe that the Mac is the best computer. Apple has won the marketing game just like Bose has done with speakers. Audiophiles say that if you want no highs or lows, you buy Bose!  Most people just don&amp;rsquo;t seem to get that while Apple does provide a good product, they are overpriced for what they provide and it isn&amp;rsquo;t close to the value most Windows-based computers are. Yes, you can find value with Linux but most people are more comfortable with what they already have been using for years &amp;ndash; Windows.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why I love GL.iNet products</title>
      <link>https://www.theexpattech.com/tech-tips/why-i-love-gl.inet-products/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 19:35:49 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.theexpattech.com/tech-tips/why-i-love-gl.inet-products/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-i-use-glinet-products-for-digital-nomad-vpns&#34;&gt;Why I use GL.iNet products for &amp;ldquo;Digital Nomad VPNs&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A few years back, a friend of mine had a work-from-home job that required her to work from a specific location.  Unfortunately for her, a relative had gotten sick and needed her to go live with them for a few weeks while they recovered.  She asked her boss if she could temporarily work from another state at a site 120 miles away.  Her boss would not allow her to do so.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is a Digital Nomad VPN?</title>
      <link>https://www.theexpattech.com/digital-nomading/what-is-a-digital-nomad-vpn/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 19:35:49 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.theexpattech.com/digital-nomading/what-is-a-digital-nomad-vpn/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;digital-nomad-vpn-guide&#34;&gt;Digital Nomad VPN Guide&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s start this off with a few explanations so you can better understand some basic concepts.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;First, think of the Internet as a giant map. There are addresses where you can access specific things, and only those addresses. To reach them, you type in something like &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.IDontWantToBeHere.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener noreffer &#34;&gt;www.IDontWantToBeHere.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; (I don’t think that site actually exists) and hit enter in your web browser. Most people don’t know how that actually works. Your Internet provider takes that website’s URL and looks it up in a “phone book” until it finds a “phone number” used to dial that location. When you enter that address, the phone book shows the address &lt;em&gt;127.0.0.1&lt;/em&gt; and dials that number. It’s that simple.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Archangel</title>
      <link>https://www.theexpattech.com/aviation/archangel/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.theexpattech.com/aviation/archangel/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Kelly Johnson&amp;rsquo;s drawings of the Archangel designs alongside Convair&amp;rsquo;s competing Fish and Kingfish concepts.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img&#xA;        class=&#34;lazyload&#34;&#xA;        src=&#34;https://www.theexpattech.com/svg/loading.min.svg&#34;&#xA;        data-src=&#34;https://www.theexpattech.com/aviation/archangel/a-1-archangel.jpg&#34;&#xA;        data-srcset=&#34;https://www.theexpattech.com/aviation/archangel/a-1-archangel.jpg, https://www.theexpattech.com/aviation/archangel/a-1-archangel.jpg 1.5x, https://www.theexpattech.com/aviation/archangel/a-1-archangel.jpg 2x&#34;&#xA;        data-sizes=&#34;auto&#34;&#xA;        alt=&#34;/aviation/archangel/a-1-archangel.jpg&#34;&#xA;        title=&#34;The A-1&#34; width=&#34;792&#34; height=&#34;594&#34; /&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;The A‑1 was Lockheed’s first attempt at a U‑2 successor. It was essentially a paper study with a long fuselage and conventional wings, but it lacked the performance needed to outrun Soviet defenses. It showed Johnson’s team was thinking about speed and altitude but hadn’t yet solved the radar visibility problem.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facts You May Not Know About U.S. Aviation</title>
      <link>https://www.theexpattech.com/aviation/facts-you-may-not-know-about-us-aviation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.theexpattech.com/aviation/facts-you-may-not-know-about-us-aviation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Throughout the 20th century, the United States achieved countless innovations in aviation. From Orville and Wilbur Wright’s first flight at Kitty Hawk, NC, to today’s advanced aircraft, there have been milestones that would have seemed impossible to the generation before.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I break down my favorite airplanes into three eras: World War II and before, the Cold War, and Modern Day. I know that’s a small number of categories compared to the full scope of aviation advances, but I’m organizing them this way as I start building my website. My goal is to generate as many stories as possible so there’s plenty of content for everyone. Believe me when I say this page will continue to grow with ongoing updates and additions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to fix an IPv6 speed issue</title>
      <link>https://www.theexpattech.com/tech-tips/how-to-fix-an-ipv6-speed-issue/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.theexpattech.com/tech-tips/how-to-fix-an-ipv6-speed-issue/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently had a big problem develop with my Digital Nomad VPN Internet Service at my home in Cuernavaca, Mexico. My ISP implemented their IPv6 migration and all sorts of problems developed. My SpeedTest.net and other links were all out of whack. I ran SpeedTest.net checks against their servers and with other servers in the Mexico City area. The results were quite surprising.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There is NOTHING wrong with the upload speed here! (sarcasm)&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;img&#xA;        class=&#34;lazyload&#34;&#xA;        src=&#34;https://www.theexpattech.com/svg/loading.min.svg&#34;&#xA;        data-src=&#34;https://www.theexpattech.com/tech-tips/how-to-fix-an-ipv6-speed-issue/test1.png&#34;&#xA;        data-srcset=&#34;https://www.theexpattech.com/tech-tips/how-to-fix-an-ipv6-speed-issue/test1.png, https://www.theexpattech.com/tech-tips/how-to-fix-an-ipv6-speed-issue/test1.png 1.5x, https://www.theexpattech.com/tech-tips/how-to-fix-an-ipv6-speed-issue/test1.png 2x&#34;&#xA;        data-sizes=&#34;auto&#34;&#xA;        alt=&#34;/tech-tips/how-to-fix-an-ipv6-speed-issue/test1.png&#34;&#xA;        title=&#34;speedtest #1&#34; width=&#34;800&#34; height=&#34;421&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Amazing SR-71</title>
      <link>https://www.theexpattech.com/aviation/the-amazing-sr-71/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.theexpattech.com/aviation/the-amazing-sr-71/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-blackbird&#34;&gt;The Blackbird&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Many people don’t realize there were actually &lt;strong&gt;two aircraft nicknamed the Blackbird&lt;/strong&gt;. The first was the &lt;strong&gt;A‑12&lt;/strong&gt;, built by the CIA as a single‑seat reconnaissance aircraft. It was designated “A‑12” because it was the twelfth design in the &lt;em&gt;Archangel&lt;/em&gt; series — “Archangel” being the program’s code name.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Lockheed and Convair competed to build a replacement for the U‑2, which had become vulnerable to Soviet radar and missiles. The CIA initially favored Convair’s Kingfish design, but Lockheed’s A‑12 offered better specifications at lower cost. Track record mattered too: Convair’s B‑58 Hustler had been plagued by delays and overruns, while Lockheed had delivered the U‑2 on time and under budget.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Becoming a Digital Nomad</title>
      <link>https://www.theexpattech.com/digital-nomading/becoming-a-digital-nomad/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.theexpattech.com/digital-nomading/becoming-a-digital-nomad/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You’re feeling wanderlust. Your job is online, so you realize you can start working from anywhere. You decide to give it a try. You research the rules and requirements for traveling the world while working remotely — and that’s how the journey begins. This site explains &lt;em&gt;my&lt;/em&gt; path down that rabbit hole.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In my case, it came about as a necessity. I was on my way to graduate school in Germany when illness cut those plans short. Looking for alternatives, I researched the best places to live for six months before trying again.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SR-71 Specifications</title>
      <link>https://www.theexpattech.com/aviation/sr-71-specifications/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.theexpattech.com/aviation/sr-71-specifications/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;general-characteristics&#34;&gt;General Characteristics&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;dimensions-and-capacities&#34;&gt;Dimensions and Capacities&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;table&gt;&#xA;  &lt;thead&gt;&#xA;      &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;          &lt;th&gt;Specification&lt;/th&gt;&#xA;          &lt;th&gt;Value&lt;/th&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/thead&gt;&#xA;  &lt;tbody&gt;&#xA;      &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Crew&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;      &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Length&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;107 ft 5 in (32.74 m)&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;      &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wingspan&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;55 ft 7 in (16.94 m)&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;      &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Height&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;18 ft 6 in (5.64 m)&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;      &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wheel track&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;16 ft 8 in (5.00 m)&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;      &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wheelbase&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;37 ft 10 in (12.00 m)&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;      &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Aspect ratio&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;1.7&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;      &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wing area&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;1,800 sq ft (170 sq m)&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;      &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Empty weight&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;67,500 lbs (30,617 kg)&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;      &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gross weight&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;152,000 lbs (68,946 kg)&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;      &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Max takeoff weight&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;172,000 lbs (78,018 kg)&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;      &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fuel capacity&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;12,219 US gal (46,255 L)&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;      &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Powerplant&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;2 × Pratt &amp;amp; Whitney J58&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/tbody&gt;&#xA;&lt;/table&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;context&#34;&gt;Context&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The SR‑71’s &lt;strong&gt;crew of two&lt;/strong&gt; (pilot and reconnaissance systems officer) was essential: one flew the aircraft, the other managed sensors and navigation at extreme speeds.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Its &lt;strong&gt;length of 107 feet&lt;/strong&gt; made it longer than a Boeing 737, yet its &lt;strong&gt;wingspan of only 55 feet&lt;/strong&gt; gave it a sleek, dart‑like profile optimized for supersonic flight.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;aspect ratio of 1.7&lt;/strong&gt; shows how stubby the wings were — designed for speed, not maneuverability.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;fuel capacity of over 12,000 gallons&lt;/strong&gt; was necessary because the J58 engines consumed fuel at astonishing rates. Even then, the SR‑71 often required multiple aerial refuelings during missions.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Pratt &amp;amp; Whitney J58 engines&lt;/strong&gt; were unique: they operated as turbojets at lower speeds but transitioned to a hybrid turbojet/ramjet mode above Mach 2.5, allowing sustained Mach 3+ flight.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;performance&#34;&gt;Performance&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;table&gt;&#xA;  &lt;thead&gt;&#xA;      &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;          &lt;th&gt;Specification&lt;/th&gt;&#xA;          &lt;th&gt;Value&lt;/th&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/thead&gt;&#xA;  &lt;tbody&gt;&#xA;      &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Maximum speed&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;1,910 kn (2,200 mph)&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;      &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Maximum Mach&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;Mach 3.3+&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;      &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ferry range&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;2,824 nmi (3,250 mi)&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;      &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Service ceiling&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;85,000 ft&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;      &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rate of climb&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;11,820 ft/min&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;      &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wing loading&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;84 lbs/sq ft&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/tbody&gt;&#xA;&lt;/table&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;context-1&#34;&gt;Context&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The SR‑71’s &lt;strong&gt;maximum speed of 2,200 mph&lt;/strong&gt; meant it could outrun threats rather than dodge them. Pilots often joked that “speed was life.”&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Its &lt;strong&gt;Mach 3.3+ capability&lt;/strong&gt; wasn’t just a headline number — the aircraft could cruise at those speeds for hours, something no other operational jet has matched.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;service ceiling of 85,000 feet&lt;/strong&gt; placed it well above most surface‑to‑air missile envelopes and fighter interceptors. Pilots reported seeing the curvature of the Earth and the deep black of space.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A &lt;strong&gt;rate of climb of nearly 12,000 ft/min&lt;/strong&gt; allowed the SR‑71 to reach operational altitude quickly, minimizing exposure during takeoff and ascent.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;wing loading of 84 lbs/sq ft&lt;/strong&gt; reflected its design trade‑off: small wings for speed meant high wing loading, making the aircraft less agile but perfectly suited for straight‑line reconnaissance runs.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;notes&#34;&gt;Notes&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;All dimensions are approximate.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Weights reflect a typical operational configuration.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Speeds represent maximum achievable under optimal conditions.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;context-2&#34;&gt;Context&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The SR‑71’s numbers don’t tell the whole story. Its titanium skin expanded several inches during flight due to heat, which is why the aircraft leaked fuel on the ground — the seals only tightened at high speeds.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The aircraft’s performance envelope was so extreme that even routine missions required careful planning of refueling points, weather conditions, and threat assessments.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Despite its complexity, the SR‑71 flew for over 30 years without ever being shot down, cementing its reputation as one of the greatest engineering achievements in aviation history.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Blackbird Family Comparison</title>
      <link>https://www.theexpattech.com/aviation/the-blackbird-family-comparison/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.theexpattech.com/aviation/the-blackbird-family-comparison/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;-blackbird-family-comparison-a-12-yf-12-and-sr-71&#34;&gt;✈️ Blackbird Family Comparison: A-12, YF-12, and SR-71&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Blackbird family represents one of the most remarkable lineages in aviation history. Born from Lockheed’s Skunk Works during the height of the Cold War, these aircraft pushed the limits of speed, altitude, and stealth. The &lt;strong&gt;A‑12&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;YF‑12&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;SR‑71&lt;/strong&gt; were closely related in design but served very different missions: clandestine CIA reconnaissance, high‑speed interception, and long‑range USAF strategic reconnaissance. Together, they showcase how a single airframe concept evolved into multiple specialized roles — each breaking records and shaping aerospace engineering for decades to come.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>You have to support your child(ren)</title>
      <link>https://www.theexpattech.com/misc/you-have-to-support-your-children/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.theexpattech.com/misc/you-have-to-support-your-children/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am going to write this as a narrative as I found about it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I was at a friend&amp;rsquo;s house on October 3, 2025 when she asked me if I had a picture of my son.  I told her I didn&amp;rsquo;t have one on me but explained that I know his work&amp;rsquo;s website had one on there.  I proceeded to go there on my phone and found my son&amp;rsquo;s section on it.  There was a big problem though - it was a different name with my son&amp;rsquo;s photo.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Network Troubleshooting Scripts</title>
      <link>https://www.theexpattech.com/tech-tips/network-troubleshooting-scripts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 19:35:49 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.theexpattech.com/tech-tips/network-troubleshooting-scripts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently had problems with my Digital Nomad VPN setup.  I went to the GL.iNet Discord and asked for help but they wanted results from various tests to be able to help me.  I provided those responses but felt there had to be a better way.&#xA;I saw these types of questions asked all the time in the tech support sub of GL.iNet&amp;rsquo;s Discourd.  I found that there were very few options out there that allowed you to find a single, simple source with logs to troubleshoot a VPN network and decided to create my own.  With the assistance of &amp;ldquo;Wicked Yoda&amp;rdquo;, I created these and shared them.  Wicked has taken on the torch to building these troubleshooting tools.  You can find them here:  &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/wickedyoda/Network-Diag-Utilities&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener noreffer &#34;&gt;https://github.com/wickedyoda/Network-Diag-Utilities&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to my world</title>
      <link>https://www.theexpattech.com/digital-nomading/welcome-to-my-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.theexpattech.com/digital-nomading/welcome-to-my-world/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;well-what-is-this-site&#34;&gt;Well, what is this site?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I want to create a place where I can share the things I enjoy, the things I know well, and the things I’ve spent a lifetime immersed in. I know a lot about computers. I’m an American who lives part-time in Mexico, part-time in the U.S., and part-time all over the world. I’ve worked professionally as an IT technician for over three decades. I also know quite a bit about how to entertain yourself if you&amp;rsquo;re an indoor person who likes movies and TV shows.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Misadventures in Moving - Day 3</title>
      <link>https://www.theexpattech.com/living-in-mexico/the-misadventures-in-moving-day-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.theexpattech.com/living-in-mexico/the-misadventures-in-moving-day-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The next morning, I get up, get on my laptop and contact a friend from boarding school that lives in Mexico City.  Pedro gives me some tips for the rest of my trip into Mexico - always tip people 10 pesos or so if they fill your gas tank (Mexico is a &amp;ldquo;full service&amp;rdquo; country where you cannot fill your own gas tank!), and gives us the name of the place to go to exchange our US dollars for pesos.  Dipshit Farmers had gone to Mexico before but they took US dollars and we thought it was that way still.  NOPE!  Mexico implemented new rules that was intended to stop money-laundering.  Anyhow, Pedro tells us to go to a &amp;ldquo;casa de cambio&amp;rdquo; to get that done.  We find one on the map and program it into my wife&amp;rsquo;s GPS.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Misadventures in Moving - Day 2</title>
      <link>https://www.theexpattech.com/living-in-mexico/the-misadventures-in-moving-day-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.theexpattech.com/living-in-mexico/the-misadventures-in-moving-day-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We wake up the next morning and it is late - 11 AM or so.  We wanted to sleep and be on the road by 9am but that just didn&amp;rsquo;t happen.  I sneak the cats back into the van and we start on the move once more.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As we are driving away, we noticed that the air conditioneer wasn&amp;rsquo;t blowing cold.  I had just put freon in yesterday before we left Albuquerque!!!!  I decide to go get more freon and put it in in the parking lot by the Motel 6.  When I go to put it in, I noticed my error.  I forgot to put the cap on the line yesterday so all the freon came out!!!  I can be an idiot at times!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Misadventures in Moving - Day 1</title>
      <link>https://www.theexpattech.com/living-in-mexico/the-misadventures-in-moving-day-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.theexpattech.com/living-in-mexico/the-misadventures-in-moving-day-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Moving to Mexico was a rushed endeavor for us.  We were moving down to Mexico in a used minivan that we bought just for the move.  You cannot rent a U-Haul to move across international borders.  The van we bought has cheap and the plan was to get to Mexico and then just get rid of it.  That turns out not to be something you can do.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To say we were not properly prepared for this move is an understatement of the century.  We were basing things on what we knew about living in the United States, and from our couple of trips to Puerto Penasco, Mexico AKA Rocky Point, or, as my girlfriend at the time kept calling Pina Colada because she was drunk.  Needless to say, things changed!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How I became a digital nomad?</title>
      <link>https://www.theexpattech.com/digital-nomading/how-i-became-a-digital-nomad/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.theexpattech.com/digital-nomading/how-i-became-a-digital-nomad/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was on my way to graduate school in Germany back in 2015.  I got as far as Amsterdam when I ended up being hospitalized for 15 days.  7 days in was when graduate school started.  The Germans wouldn&amp;rsquo;t let me have a late start so I had to return to the US.  We had already sold our house by then so I needed to move somewhere fast.  My requirements were that the place was inexpensive, had great internet service, was near a major international airport, and that &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;snow&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo; was a foreign language and the only ice you got was in your drink.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How and why I moved to Mexico?</title>
      <link>https://www.theexpattech.com/living-in-mexico/how-and-why-i-moved-to-mexico/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.theexpattech.com/living-in-mexico/how-and-why-i-moved-to-mexico/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I got in my van and drove there! ;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Okay, I will be serious.  I really didn&amp;rsquo;t have a choice but to move.  In my case, I had just come home from a failed attempt to start school in Germany.  We were in a bad situation - we had sold our house already, needed to move to somewhere for 6 months and live on a student&amp;rsquo;s budget.  We needed to have good Internet, be near a major international airport, and inexpensive.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
