<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>The Expat Tech</title>
        <link>https://theexpattech.com/</link>
        <description>This is my cool site</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 00:00:00 &#43;0000</lastBuildDate>
            <atom:link href="https://theexpattech.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <item>
    <title>GL.iNet Beryl AX review</title>
    <link>https://theexpattech.com/posts/posts/tech-tips/gl.inet-beryl-ax-review/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>ZDevilInside</author>
    <guid>https://theexpattech.com/posts/posts/tech-tips/gl.inet-beryl-ax-review/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<h1 id="-glinet-beryl-ax-gl-mt3000-review">🌐 GL.iNet Beryl AX (GL-MT3000) Review</h1>
<p></p>
<p>I know this is an older piece of hardware that is about to have its follow on Beryl 7 released but this router is a staple of many a digital nomader&rsquo;s equipment. I have been using one for years without issue and I feel that it is a budget VPN router worth knowing about.  You can easily take it with you, use it in &ldquo;capture portal&rdquo; situations, and it gives you a separate network that all your devices can connect to.  Oh, and it can run a Wireguard client/server as needed along with several other VPN solutions.</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Resetting a Flipper Zero</title>
    <link>https://theexpattech.com/posts/posts/tech-tips/resetting-a-flipper-zero/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 14:35:49 -0600</pubDate>
    <author>ZDevilInside</author>
    <guid>https://theexpattech.com/posts/posts/tech-tips/resetting-a-flipper-zero/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>Do you have a Flipper Zero that you forgot the pin to?  It is actually quite easy to reset.</p>
<table>
  <thead>
      <tr>
          <th></th>
          <th></th>
      </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
      <tr>
          <td>1.  Remove the microSD card from the device.</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>2.  Hold the UP and BACK buttons for 30 seconds.</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>3.  When it asks you if you want to reset, push the right button to confirm that you want to reset it.</td>
          <td>:)</td>
      </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>
<p>If that doesn&rsquo;t work, you will need to run qFlipper.</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>What is a Digital Nomad VPN?</title>
    <link>https://theexpattech.com/posts/posts/digital-nomading/what-is-a-digital-nomad-vpn/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 19:35:49 -0600</pubDate>
    <author>ZDevilInside</author>
    <guid>https://theexpattech.com/posts/posts/digital-nomading/what-is-a-digital-nomad-vpn/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Let&rsquo;s start this off with a few explanations of things so you can better understand some basic concepts.</strong></p>
<p>First off, think of the Internet as a giant map.  There are addresses on there that you can get certain things from and only those addresses.  To reach them, you type in something like <a href="https://www.IDontWantToBeHere.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">www.IDontWantToBeHere.com</a> (I don&rsquo;t think that site actually exists though) and hit enter on your web browser.  Most people don&rsquo;t know how that actually works though.  Your Internet provider takes that website&rsquo;s URL and looks it up in a phone book until it gets a &ldquo;phone number&rdquo; that is used to dial that location.  When you enter that address, the phonebook shows the address 127.0.0.1 and dials that #.  It is that simple.</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Digital Nomad VPN Setup</title>
    <link>https://theexpattech.com/posts/posts/digital-nomading/digital-nomad-vpn-setup/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>ZDevilInside</author>
    <guid>https://theexpattech.com/posts/posts/digital-nomading/digital-nomad-vpn-setup/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<h1 id="top-secret---unauthorized-personnel-will-be-shot-if-they-continue-to-read-this-post">Top Secret - Unauthorized personnel will be shot if they continue to read this post&hellip;..</h1>
<p>Okay, you have made the decision.  You want to take a chance with your job and work from somewhere that you are not authorized.  You now need to set things up so that you can make it the least likely to get caught.  You agree not to hold me responsible for any outcome you have if you are caught doing what I am about to show you how to do.</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Build a Mac OS 15 Sequoia VM?</title>
    <link>https://theexpattech.com/posts/posts/tech-tips/build-a-mac-os-15-sequoia-vm/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 19:35:49 -0600</pubDate>
    <author>ZDevilInside</author>
    <guid>https://theexpattech.com/posts/posts/tech-tips/build-a-mac-os-15-sequoia-vm/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<h2 id="getting-started">Getting Started</h2>
<p><strong>How to create a MacOS 15 Sequoia VM in VMware</strong></p>
<p>Over the years, I have noticed that a lot of people seem to have bought into the marketing of Apple and believe that the Mac is the best computer. Apple has won the marketing game just like Bose has done with speakers. Audiophiles say that if you want no highs or lows, you buy Bose!  Most people just don&rsquo;t seem to get that while Apple does provide a good product, they are overpriced for what they provide and it isn&rsquo;t close to the value most Windows-based computers are. Yes, you can find value with Linux but most people are more comfortable with what they already have been using for years &ndash; Windows.</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Network Troubleshooting Scripts</title>
    <link>https://theexpattech.com/posts/posts/tech-tips/network-troubleshooting-scripts/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 19:35:49 -0600</pubDate>
    <author>ZDevilInside</author>
    <guid>https://theexpattech.com/posts/posts/tech-tips/network-troubleshooting-scripts/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>I recently had problems with my Digital Nomad VPN setup.  I went to the GL.iNet Discord and asked for help but they wanted results from various tests to be able to help me.  I provided those responses but felt there had to be a better way.
I saw these types of questions asked all the time in the tech support sub of GL.iNet&rsquo;s Discourd.  I found that there were very few options out there that allowed you to find a single, simple source with logs to troubleshoot a VPN network and decided to create my own.  With the assistance of &ldquo;Wicked Yoda&rdquo;, I created these and shared them.  Wicked has taken on the torch to building these troubleshooting tools.  You can find them here:  <a href="https://github.com/wickedyoda/Network-Diag-Utilities" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">https://github.com/wickedyoda/Network-Diag-Utilities</a></p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Archangel</title>
    <link>https://theexpattech.com/posts/posts/aviation/archangel/</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>ZDevilInside</author>
    <guid>https://theexpattech.com/posts/posts/aviation/archangel/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>Kelly Johnson&rsquo;s drawings of the Archangel design alonside Convair&rsquo;s drawings of the Fish series.</p>
<p>
The A-2 design

Convair Fish design

A-7 - A-9 designs

A-10 Design

Corvair Kingfish design
</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Becoming a Digital Nomad</title>
    <link>https://theexpattech.com/posts/posts/digital-nomading/becoming-a-digital-nomad/</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>ZDevilInside</author>
    <guid>https://theexpattech.com/posts/posts/digital-nomading/becoming-a-digital-nomad/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>You are feeling wunderlust.  Your job is online so you feel that you can start working from anywhere.  You decide to give it a go.  You look online at the rules needed to travel the world while working online.  That is how you get your start.  This site will explain <em>my</em> path down this rabbit hole.</p>
<p>In my case, it came about as a necessity.  I was on my way to graduate school in Germany when that was cut short due to illness.  I looked around and did research online for the best places to go and live for 6 months before I gave another shot at going to Germany.</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Facts you may not know about US aviation.</title>
    <link>https://theexpattech.com/posts/posts/aviation/facts-you-may-not-know-about-us-aviation./</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>ZDevilInside</author>
    <guid>https://theexpattech.com/posts/posts/aviation/facts-you-may-not-know-about-us-aviation./</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>Throughout the 20th century, the United States has had many innovations. From Orville and Wilbur Wright&rsquo;s first flight at Kitty Hawk, NC to today, there have been numerous events that would not have been thought possible the generation before it.</p>
<p>For me, I break down my favorite airplanes into 3 areas: World War II and before, the Cold War, and Modern Day. I know that is a small number of areas compared to the advances that aviation has undertaken during that period of time. I have to break it into those areas because I am starting to put up my website and want to generate as many stories as I can prior to that happening so there is content for everyone. Believe me when I say that this page will be undergoing ongoing updates and content additions.</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>How and why I moved to Mexico?</title>
    <link>https://theexpattech.com/posts/posts/living-in-mexico/how-and-why-i-moved-to-mexico/</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>ZDevilInside</author>
    <guid>https://theexpattech.com/posts/posts/living-in-mexico/how-and-why-i-moved-to-mexico/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>I got in my van and drove there! ;)</p>
<p>Okay, I will be serious.  I really didn&rsquo;t have a choice but to move.  In my case, I had just come home from a failed attempt to start school in Germany.  We were in a bad situation - we had sold our house already, needed to move to somewhere for 6 months and live on a student&rsquo;s budget.  We needed to have good Internet, be near a major international airport, and inexpensive.</p>]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
