<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Digital Nomading on The Expat Tech</title>
    <link>https://www.theexpattech.com/categories/digital-nomading/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Digital Nomading on The Expat Tech</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.theexpattech.com/categories/digital-nomading/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Recommended VPN Equipment</title>
      <link>https://www.theexpattech.com/digital-nomading/vpn-equipment-i-use/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.theexpattech.com/digital-nomading/vpn-equipment-i-use/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am a true believer in using &lt;strong&gt;GL.iNet equipment&lt;/strong&gt; for setting up Digital Nomad VPNs. My recommendation comes from years of hands‑on experience with these devices.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Originally, I learned how to set up a VPN server/client by searching the web — and nearly gave up when faced with overwhelming technical jargon. Eventually, I found a website that walked me through the process step by step. The very first recommendation was simple but vital: &lt;em&gt;buy the right equipment&lt;/em&gt;. It sounds obvious, but many of us overlook this step. I certainly had!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GL.iNet Beryl AX review</title>
      <link>https://www.theexpattech.com/tech-tips/gl.inet-beryl-ax-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.theexpattech.com/tech-tips/gl.inet-beryl-ax-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;-glinet-beryl-ax-gl-mt3000-review&#34;&gt;🌐 GL.iNet Beryl AX (GL-MT3000) Review&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img&#xA;        class=&#34;lazyload&#34;&#xA;        src=&#34;https://www.theexpattech.com/svg/loading.min.svg&#34;&#xA;        data-src=&#34;https://www.theexpattech.com/tech-tips/gl.inet-beryl-ax-review/Tech-Tips/beryl-ax-review/image1.jpg&#34;&#xA;        data-srcset=&#34;https://www.theexpattech.com/tech-tips/gl.inet-beryl-ax-review/Tech-Tips/beryl-ax-review/image1.jpg, https://www.theexpattech.com/tech-tips/gl.inet-beryl-ax-review/Tech-Tips/beryl-ax-review/image1.jpg 1.5x, https://www.theexpattech.com/tech-tips/gl.inet-beryl-ax-review/Tech-Tips/beryl-ax-review/image1.jpg 2x&#34;&#xA;        data-sizes=&#34;auto&#34;&#xA;        alt=&#34;/tech-tips/gl.inet-beryl-ax-review/Tech-Tips/beryl-ax-review/image1.jpg&#34;&#xA;        title=&#34;image 1&#34; width=&#34;800&#34; height=&#34;1067&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;GL.iNet Beryl AX (GL-MT3000)&lt;/strong&gt; may not be the newest device on the market—with the Beryl 7 on the horizon—but it remains a staple in many digital nomads’ gear bags. I’ve used mine for years without issue, and it continues to be one of the most reliable budget VPN routers available.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It’s compact, easy to set up, and perfect for situations where you need a secure, private network on the go. Whether you’re connecting in a hotel, café, or airport lounge, the Beryl AX gives you control and peace of mind.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Digital Nomad VPN Setup</title>
      <link>https://www.theexpattech.com/digital-nomading/digital-nomad-vpn-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.theexpattech.com/digital-nomading/digital-nomad-vpn-setup/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;-top-secret-notice&#34;&gt;🚨 Top Secret Notice&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unauthorized personnel beware!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;This guide contains sensitive setup instructions.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Proceed at your own risk — and remember, this is for educational purposes only.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Okay, you have made the decision. You want to take a chance with your job and work from somewhere that you are not authorized. You now need to set things up so that you can make it the least likely to get caught. You agree not to hold me responsible for any outcome you have if you are caught doing what I am about to show you how to do.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is a Digital Nomad VPN?</title>
      <link>https://www.theexpattech.com/digital-nomading/what-is-a-digital-nomad-vpn/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 19:35:49 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.theexpattech.com/digital-nomading/what-is-a-digital-nomad-vpn/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;digital-nomad-vpn-guide&#34;&gt;Digital Nomad VPN Guide&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s start this off with a few explanations so you can better understand some basic concepts.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;First, think of the Internet as a giant map. There are addresses where you can access specific things, and only those addresses. To reach them, you type in something like &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.IDontWantToBeHere.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener noreffer &#34;&gt;www.IDontWantToBeHere.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; (I don’t think that site actually exists) and hit enter in your web browser. Most people don’t know how that actually works. Your Internet provider takes that website’s URL and looks it up in a “phone book” until it finds a “phone number” used to dial that location. When you enter that address, the phone book shows the address &lt;em&gt;127.0.0.1&lt;/em&gt; and dials that number. It’s that simple.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Becoming a Digital Nomad</title>
      <link>https://www.theexpattech.com/digital-nomading/becoming-a-digital-nomad/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.theexpattech.com/digital-nomading/becoming-a-digital-nomad/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You’re feeling wanderlust. Your job is online, so you realize you can start working from anywhere. You decide to give it a try. You research the rules and requirements for traveling the world while working remotely — and that’s how the journey begins. This site explains &lt;em&gt;my&lt;/em&gt; path down that rabbit hole.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In my case, it came about as a necessity. I was on my way to graduate school in Germany when illness cut those plans short. Looking for alternatives, I researched the best places to live for six months before trying again.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to my world</title>
      <link>https://www.theexpattech.com/digital-nomading/welcome-to-my-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.theexpattech.com/digital-nomading/welcome-to-my-world/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;well-what-is-this-site&#34;&gt;Well, what is this site?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I want to create a place where I can share the things I enjoy, the things I know well, and the things I’ve spent a lifetime immersed in. I know a lot about computers. I’m an American who lives part‑time in Mexico, part‑time in the U.S., and part‑time all over the world. I’ve worked professionally as an IT technician for over three decades. I also know quite a bit about how to entertain yourself if you&amp;rsquo;re an indoor person who likes movies and TV shows.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How I Became a Digital Nomad?</title>
      <link>https://www.theexpattech.com/digital-nomading/how-i-became-a-digital-nomad/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.theexpattech.com/digital-nomading/how-i-became-a-digital-nomad/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In 2015, I was on my way to graduate school in Germany. I made it as far as Amsterdam when I was unexpectedly hospitalized for 15 days. Unfortunately, the program began on the seventh day of my stay, and the German university would not allow a late start. My plans collapsed, and I had to return to the United States.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;By then, we had already sold our house, so I needed to find a new place to live quickly. My requirements were clear: the location had to be inexpensive, have reliable high‑speed internet, be near a major international airport, and — most importantly — be somewhere warm, where “snow” was a foreign word and the only ice you encountered was in your drink.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
